https://davisonvets.co.uk/privacy-policy/

West Bridgford
Privacy policyThis practice (“the Practice”) is a member of the CVS (UK) Limited group of veterinary practices (“CVS”). When you register with the Practice, request treatment for your animal, contact the practice by email, telephone or in writing we will collect and process personal information (“Personal Information”) about you.
We understand the importance of looking after the Personal Information that you provide and this notice (“Privacy Notice”) sets out what Personal Information we collect, why we need to collect it, how we will use it and how long we will store it for.
How we will use your personal information
We will process your Personal Information insofar as it is necessary for the performance of our contract with you to provide veterinary services. This will involve using your Personal Information to provide you with our products and services and to send you information related to the services we provide to you including appointment and vaccination reminders (“Service Communications”). You can choose how you would like to receive these communications by post, email or SMS. Please talk to one of our members of staff if you would like to change how you receive Service Communications.
What personal information do we collect and why
Name – So that We can identify You and personalise our communications with You.
Address – So that We can identify You, register your animal with our practice send reminders, correspondence and information about our services directly to you and to send information about local animal health issues.
Email address – So that we can contact you about your Animal, send reminders about your appointments, vaccinations, flea or worming treatments and or correspondence about our service and animal health issues.
Mobile number – So that we can contact you about your Animal, send reminders about your appointments, vaccinations, flea or worming treatments and or correspondence about our service and animal health issues.
Telephone number – So that we can contact you about your Animal.
Location information (such as postcode) – So that we can inform you about any animal health concerns we are aware of in your area.
Bank, debit or credit card details – So that we can receive payment for the services we provide if applicable.
Insurance policy number – So that we can communicate with your animal insurance provider if applicable.
Please remember to let Practice staff know if any of the above information changes as soon as possible so that we have up to date records. Our staff will ask you to confirm your records are up to date on a regular basis.
Marketing
In addition to our contractual services, we would like to process your Personal Information with your consent to send you information about other products and services available from the Practice or CVS. You will be asked for your consent when you register with the Practice and we will refresh your consent on a regular basis. You can change your mind at any time and unsubscribe or subscribe by talking to staff in our practice of by following the links on any marketing emails you receive.
Data retention
We will keep your Personal Information for as long as you are a client of our Practice or another practice in the CVS group and thereafter for as long as any legal claim may be made against the Practice, CVS or our colleagues and for as long as is required to comply with our legal and regulatory requirements including to the HMRC and RCVS.
Sharing your information
We are required to share your Personal Information in certain circumstances to ensure that we are able to provide you with services, obtain payment or correspond with your insurance provider. In each case we will only share the data necessary for the purpose and it will only be in relation to the specified purpose. Each third party is required to have in place comparable data security measures and to be fully compliant with the terms of the General Data Protection Regulations.
Who do we share information with and why
Referral practices
When we refer an animal to a referral hospital or specialist, we need to share relevant information to arrange appointments, test, treatments and services.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your address.
Your email address.
Mobile number.
Telephone number.
Laboratories and Animal Crematorium
So that we can arrange tests, treatments and services and obtain results on your behalf.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your address.
Your insurer
So that we can obtain permission to perform certain investigations and treatments at their expense. To arrange payment for investigations and treatments provided.
Information do we share:
Insurance policy number.
Your name.
Your address.
Banks and payment service providers
So that we can deal with payments for the appointments, services, treatments and goods provided. To make refunds.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your account details.
Your address.
Credit reference and fraud prevention agencies
We may share your personal information with and obtain information about you from credit reference agencies or fraud prevention agencies.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your address.
Debt collection agencies
If you fall behind with payments for the services we provide, we may engage a debt collection agency to recover the debt on our behalf.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your address.
Your outstanding balance.
Email providers, printers and mailing houses
So that we can send you reminders, administrative information relating to the way we provide services to you, information about animal health issues relevant to you and marketing communications if you have consented to receiving them.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your address.
Your email address.
Law enforcement agencies
If we receive a request in writing from a law enforcement agency, we may be required to provide your personal information.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your address.
Your email address.
Mobile number.
Telephone number.
Location information.
Bank, debit or credit card details.
Insurance policy number.
CVS (UK) Limited
So that we can provide administrative and support services to our practices to ensure you receive the best possible care.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your address.
Your email address.
Mobile number.
Telephone number.
Location information.
Bank, debit or credit card details.
Insurance policy number.
Moving practice
If you decide to move to a new practice we will provide a copy of your animals’ records to the new practice when requested. If you do not want your records transferred, please speak to a member of the Practice staff.
Information do we share:
Your name.
Your address.
Your email address.
Mobile number.
Telephone number.
Save as set out above, we will not sell, lease or transfer your personal information to any other person or company without your prior consent.
Keeping your data secure
We recognise the importance of keeping your personal data safe and we have in place security measures and policies to prevent personal data from being lost, used or accessed without our permission. We limit access to your Personal Information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.
Your rights
The General Data Protection Regulation grants all data subjects the following rights without charge. These include the right to:
Fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your use Personal Information;
Access your Personal Information and to certain other supplementary information that this Privacy Notice is already designed to address;
Require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold;
Require the erasure of Personal Information concerning you in certain situations;
Receive the Personal Information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to a third party in certain situations;
Object at any time to processing of Personal Information concerning you for direct marketing;
Object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you;
Object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your Personal Information;
Otherwise restrict our processing of your Personal Information in certain circumstances.
For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, see the Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals’ rights under the General Data Protection Regulation.
If you would like to exercise any of your rights, please contact the practice manager at your Practice. In order for us to deal with your request efficiently, please provide:
Sufficient information to allow us to identify you;
Evidence of your identity and your address (for example, a copy of your driving licence or passport);
As much information about your request including, if applicable, dates, specific documents or animal names.
We will keep our privacy policy under regular review and we publish any updates in practice or on this website. This privacy policy was last updated on 1 May 2018.
How to contact us
Please contact us if you have any questions about our privacy policy or the information we hold about you.
By email: dataprotection@cvsvets.com
Or write to us at CVS House, Owen Road, Diss, IP22 4ER
CVS (UK) Limited (registered number 3777473) is a company registered in England at CVS House, Owen Road, Diss, Norfolk, IP22 4ER and is the Data Controller.
Join Today – Generic
Register
Healthy Pet Club
CVS Group plc
Get in touch
Get in touch
Call us
Email us
West Bridgford
We use cookies to give you the best possible online experience. If you continue, we'll assume you are happy for your web browser to receive all cookies from our website. See our cookie policy for more information on cookies and how to manage them. ClosePrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Non-necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
x
COVID-19 Update
We are working safely and will continue to provide care for your pets during the COVID-19 pandemic including local and national lockdowns.
To help us with our new ways of working and to keep us all safe, please do not attend the practice unless you have called us first and have a pre-booked appointment. Thank you.
Order repeat prescriptions
